Guide to the G. & C. Merriam Company Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize, 50; (40 boxes)
  - Summary of incoming correspondence from booksellers (in Series I), 1890-94 (Box 112, Folder 715)
  - Abridgments (in Series I), 1854 Apr 7 (Box 112, Folder 716)
  - G. & C. Merriam (in Series I), 1832-1909, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 717)
  - Haldeman, Samuel Stehman (in Series I), 1841-68 (Box 112, Folder 718)
  - Boston Type & Stereo Foundry (in Series I) (Box 112, Folder 719)
  - Deeds (in Series I), 1847-59 (Box 112, Folder 720)
  - G. & C. Merriam (in Series I), 1844-74 (Box 112, Folder 721)
  - Goodrich, Chauncey (in Series I), 1845-65, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 722)
  - Imperial Dictionary (in Series I), 1883 Apr (Box 112, Folder 723)
  - Iowa (in Series I), 1858-62 (Box 112, Folder 724)
  - Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co. (in Series I), 1866-90 (Box 112, Folder 725)
  - Samuel Bowles & Company (in Series I), n.d. (Box 112, Folder 726)
  - Suggested Corrections and Additions to Webster Dictionaries: Writings, printed material (in Series I), 1863-68 (Box 112, Folder 727)
  - Loose items removed from Office Interviews, 1880-1902 (in Series III), 1902-20 (Box 112, Folder 728)
  - Loose material removed from Scrapbook: Printed advertisements and testimonials (in Series IV), 1900-08, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 729)
  - Clippings, circulars, and pamphlets about the Merriams (in Series IV), 1878-1944, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 730-731)
  - A leaf from Johnson's Dictionary (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 112, Folder 732)
  - Miscellaneous printed ephemera (in Series IV), 1880-1937, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 733)
  - [Webster, Noah?] Holograph revisions to a printed dictionary page with tipped on pages carrying holograph additions (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 112, Folder 734)
  - "E" general (in Series I), 1850-80, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 735)
  - An American Dictionary, etc. - 1847 (in Series I), 1844-60 (Box 113, Folder 736)
  - An American Dictionary, etc. - 1864 (in Series I), 1861-64 (Box 113, Folder 737)
  - Suggested Corrections and Additions to Webster Dictionaries: Writings, printed material (in Series I) (Box 113, Folder 738)
  - Clippings [advertising] (in Series IV), [1806?]-1900, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 739)
  - Circulars advertising new editions (in Series IV), 1849-96, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 740)
  - Clippings about Noah Webster (in Series IV) (Box 113, Folder 741)
  - Clippings: reviews of Webster dictionaries (in Series IV), 1845-1915, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 742)
  - Galley proof and page proof for an Addenda page, corrected (in Series IV), 1926 (Box 113, Folder 743)
  - Unidentified. Printed column from unidentified dictionary, with autograph manuscript corrections (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 113, Folder 744)
  - Unidentified. Dictionary Chart (in Series IV), n.d. (Box 113, Folder 745)
  - Wheeler, William Adolphus. Covers of volumes with Wheeler correspondence previously tipped in (from Series I) (Box 114, Folder 746)
  - Covers of volumes with Suggested Corrections and Additions to Webster Dictionaries previously tipped in, 1856, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 747)
  - State, County, & City Superintendent's Book. Letterpress copybook: July 30, 1877 to December 12, 1878 (in Series II) (Box 115, Folder 748)
  - Letterpress copybook: July 29, 1882 to January 1905 (in Series II), 1882-1905 (Box 116, Folder 749)
  - E. Merriam & Co.; E. & G. Merriam account book (in Series III), 1818-32 (Box 117, Folder 750)
  - E. & G. Merriam "Leger" (in Series III), 1824-31 (Box 118, Folder 751)
  - E. Merriam & Co.; E. & G. Merriam account book (in Series III), 1828-32 (Box 119, Folder 752)
  - Ledger A. On title page: Merriam, Little & Co. August 1st, 1831. G. and C. Merriam, April 28th, 1832 (in Series III), 1831-36 (Box 120, Folder 753)
  - Ledger B (in Series III), 1836-39 (Box 121, Folder 754)
  - Ledger C (in Series III), 1840-44 (Box 122, Folder 755)
  - Ledger D (in Series III), 1843-46 (Box 123, Folder 756)
  - Ledger E (in Series III), 1846-49 (Box 124, Folder 757)
  - Ledger (in Series III), 1853-56 (Box 125, Folder 758)
  - Ledger (in Series III), 1856-65 (Box 126, Folder 759)
  - Ledger (in Series III), 1865-76 (Box 127, Folder 760)
  - Ledger (in Series III), 1876-77 (Box 128, Folder 761)
  - Ledger (in Series III), 1877-82 (Box 129, Folder 762)
  - Ledger A (in Series III), 1882-87 (Box 130, Folder 763)
  - Ledger B April 1887-March 1889 (in Series III), 1887-89 (Box 131, Folder 764)
  - Booksellers account book (in Series III), 1843-48 (Box 132, Folder 765)
  - Ledger (in Series III), 1845-47 (Box 133, Folder 766)
  - E. Merriam & Co.; E. & G. Merriam daybook (in Series III), 1828-31 (Box 134, Folder 767)
  - Merriam, Little & Co. On spine: A [daybook] (in Series III), 1831-33 (Box 135, Folder 768)
  - Merchants Accounts, No. 1 (in Series III), 1841-44 (Box 136, Folder 769)
  - On spine: B [merchants books] (in Series III), 1843-45 (Box 137, Folder 770)
  - Merriam, Little & Co. [order books] (in Series III), 1831-36 (Box 138, Folder 771)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and pamphlets (in Series IV), 1850-54 (Box 139, Folder 772)
  - Scrapbook: Newspaper notices, controversial and non-controversial (in Series IV), 1855-58 (Box 140, Folder 773)
  - Scrapbook of advertisements: pamphlets and circulars (in Series IV), 1856-83 (Box 141, Folder 774)
  - Scrapbook of clippings relating to Webster's Unabridged (in Series IV), 1864-65 (Box 142, Folder 775)
  - Scrapbook of clippings, circulars, advertisements, pamphlets relating mainly to Webster's Unabridged (in Series IV), 1864-82 (Box 143, Folder 776)
  - Scrapbook of notes on publishers, booksellers, paper companies all over the United States (in Series IV), 1866-70 (Box 144, Folder 777)
  - Scrapbook: Stationery, circulars, pamphlets, color plates (in Series IV), 1884-94 (Box 145, Folder 778)
  - Scrapbook: Printed advertisements and testimonials, etc. (in Series IV), 1900-09, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 779)
  - William A. Wheeler scrapbook of clippings, pamphlets relating to Webster Dictionaries (in Series IV), 1860-1940 (Box 147, Folder 780)
  - International Dictionary, Vol. 1: Clippings (in Series IV), 1891-95 (Box 148, Folder 781)
  - International Dictionary, Vol. 2: Clippings (in Series IV), 1892-1914 (Box 149, Folder 782)
  - International Dictionary, Vol. 3: Clippings (in Series IV), 1900-05 (Box 150, Folder 783)
  - Merriam, Homer. Annals of the Merriam Family. Bound holograph (in Series IV), 1862-1976 (Box 151, Folder 784)
  - Case, Lockwood & Co. (in Series I), 1860, 1873 (Box bsd, folder 785)
  - Clippings [advertising] (in Series IV), [1806?]-1900, n.d. (Box bsd, folder 786)
  - Clippings: reviews of Webster dictionaries (in Series IV), 1845-1915, n.d. (Box bsd, folder 787)
- Restricted Fragile
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 7, folders 7-8 (Box 152, Folder 788)
  - Box 8, folder 88 (Box 152, Folder 789)
  - Box 11, folder 171 (Box 152, Folder 790)
  - Box 12, folder 203 (Box 152, Folder 791)
  - Box 23, folder 488 (Box 152, Folder 792)
  - Box 93, folder 651 (Box 152, Folder 793)
  - Box 93, folder 652 (Box 152, Folder 794)
  - Box 94, folder 667 (Box 152, Folder 795)
  - Box 94, folders 672-673 (Box 152, Folder 796)
  - Box 101, folder 696 (Box 152, Folder 797)
  - Box 101, folder 697 (Box 152, Folder 798)
  - Box 148, folder 781 (Box 152, Folder 799)
  - Box 95, folder 685 (Box 152, Folder 800)
  - Box 12, folder 206 (Box 153, Folder 801)
  - Box 93, folder 651 (Box 153, Folder 802)
  - Box 93, folders 654-655 (Box 153, Folder 803)
  - Box 94, folders 668-669 (Box 153, Folder 804)
  - Box 95, folder 680 (Box 153, Folder 805)
  - Box 95, folder 685 (Box 153, Folder 806-807)
  - Box 101, folder 699 (Box 153, Folder 808)
  - Box 95, folder 686 (Box 154, Folder 809)
  - Box 95, folder 687 (Box 155, Folder 810)
  - Box 94, folders 668-669 (Box bsd, folder 811)